Amen. And happy Sabbath everyone. Um I
want to welcome you to Living Mana
Online Church. We are getting ready to
get into the word of God today. And I
pray that uh today's message will speak
to your heart in a very special special
way. So, uh, today's message is entitled
I Unfriend You: Satan's Dehumanization
Plot for the End Times. Pray with me,
please. Heavenly Father,
we ask in a special way, Lord, that you
would please speak through me today.
Lord, please open the eyes of your
people. And Lord, help us to know not
only what is the enemy's plan, but what
is your plan for us as well. And Lord,
may we follow that plan is our prayer in
Jesus name. Amen.
I unfriend you. Satan's dehum
dehumanization plot for the end times.
That phrase I unfriend you is a very
familiar phrase especially in our social
media um saturated world. Uh we unfriend
people
uh if we don't like what someone has
said. We unfriend people if we feel that
they have come at us in a in a wrong
way. And it is not something limited to
social media. It is something that is
happening all the time. I unfriend you.
I want to take that particular theme,
that particular thought, and I want to
trace something through the Bible for
you that by the grace of God, you will
you will have the curtains pulled back
to see what the enemy's plan is for
God's people, especially as it relates
to the end of time. So, let's go to the
screen. We're going to begin with John
chapter 15. John chapter 15, verse 12.
Jesus said these words, "This is my
commandment that you love one another as
I have loved you. Greater love has no
man than this, that a man lay down his
life for his friends. You are my friends
if you do whatsoever I command you." You
can see here that Jesus puts a high
value on friendship and he connects
friendship with love. He says, "Greater
love has no man than this than a man is
willing to lay his life down for his
friends." Friendship in God's eyes is
connected with love. Now, what I want to
show you, beloved, requires us to go
back to the book of Genesis,
uh, when God is is is creating the
world, and we're going to look at
Genesis chapter 1, uh, particularly
verse 24. In verse 24, the Bible says
these words. And God said, "Let the
earth bring forth the living creature
after his kind, cattle and creeping
things, and the beast of the earth after
his kind." And it was so. And God made
the beast of the earth after his kind,
and cattle after their kind, and
everything that creepeth upon the earth
after his kind. And God saw that it was
good. Now, Genesis 1:es 24 and 25 are
speaking to God's creating of the beasts
of the earth. And immediately after he
creates the beast of the earth, the text
now goes on to say these words. Verse
26. And God said, "Let us make man in
our image, after our likeness, and let
them have dominion over the fish of the
sea, and over the fowl of the air, and
over the cattle, and over all the earth,
and over every creeping thing that
creepeth upon the earth." So God created
man in his own image, in the image of
God created he him. Male and female
created he them. Verse 28. And God
blessed them. And God said unto them,
"Be fruitful and multiply, and replenish
the earth, and subdue it, and have
dominion over the fish of the of the
sea, and over the fowl of the air, and
over every living thing that moveth upon
the earth." What I want you to
understand here is that there is a
difference between the creation of beast
and the creation of man. Man was made in
the image of God. Beasts were not made
in the image of God. Put a one in the
chat that if you're following so far,
very simple point. When God made beasts,
they were not made in the image of God.
But when he made when God made beasts,
they were not in the image of God. But
when he made man, they were in the image
of God. Now, what does it mean that we
were made in the image of God? Um, and
beasts were not. Well, notice with me
John chapter 1, 1 John 1:4,
where the Bible says these words, "He
that loveth not knoweth not God, for God
is love."
If God is love and man was made in the
image of God, then what that means is
man was made with this beautiful
capacity to love.
It is something that beasts do not
possess. Beasts don't know how to love.
Beasts don't know how to have empathy.
Beasts don't know the qualities of a
human life. And so, man was made
specifically in the image of God.
meaning man was made huh uh with the
capacity to love. So let's get that
straight. The beasts had no capacity to
love. Man was made with a capacity to
love. Now the Bible says something
interesting in Genesis chapter 3. After
God has created man tells man not to eat
from the tree. In Genesis 3:1
the Bible says these words. Now the
serpent was more subtle than any beast
of the field which the Lord God had
made. And he said unto the woman, "Yay,
has God said, 'Ye shall not eat of every
tree of the garden." So now we have the
introduction of this serpent whom we
understand to be Satan. But this serpent
is described as a beast.
That is significant.
Uh uh the Bible tells us as the story
continues on that that Adam and Eve
ultimately listen to this beast and they
eat from the tree. And now God is going
to come to them in the garden and God is
going to speak to Adam, to Eve and the
beast. And I want you to notice what he
says in Genesis 3:14.
The Bible says here, "And the Lord God
said unto the serpent." So now he's
talking to the serpent. Because you have
done this, you are cursed above all
cattle and above every beast of the
field. Upon thy belly shalt thy go shalt
thou go. And dust shalt thou eat all the
days of thy life. And now watch this
next verse. Verse 15.
And I will put enmity between thee, that
is the serpent, this beast, and the
woman. So, we've got two categories here
being cursed.
The beast
I I shouldn't say being cursed, but two
categories that God is speaking to here
in this verse. The beast and the woman.
A and in verse 15, he says, "I will put
enmity between thee, that is the beast,
and the woman, and between thy seed
and her seed."
That's very important to understand you
guys because what the text is telling us
here is that the beast itself
would have offspring.
In other words, this offspring
of the beast would would would
represent the seed of the beast. It
would be beast seed.
So in this in this uh h uh prophecy
you have offspring of the beast and you
have offspring of the woman. One is
animal, one is human. Now we understand
that that that what is being spoken
about here in the context of both of
these seed are human beings. But please
note the significance.
One set of human beings are going to be
beastly
and the other set of human beings are
going to be human.
Human heart versus beast heart.
Human characteristics.
Characteristics made in the image of God
versus beastly characteristics.
And so
what I want you to see here is this. In
John chapter 3, 1 John chapter 3 11,
we're going to see something very
powerful here.
Before we go there, remember this that
Eve's first child is Cain.
And and Cain, we know,
comes to represent the seed of the
beast.
Even though he's born of Eve, he's
actually the seed of the beast.
meaning his character, his disposition
was very beastlike, animallike. And
notice with me 1 John 3:1, where the
Bible says, "For this is the message you
have heard from the beginning, that we
should love one another, not as Cain."
No, watch this now, guys. Watch. See the
parallel here. Love is of God.
And then it the text goes on to say not
like Cain or not as Cain.
And watch this. Who was of that wicked
one and slew his brother. And wherefore
slew he him because his own works were
evil and his brothers righteous. Marvel
not, my brethren, if the world hate you.
See that connection there? Cain
hate.
God
love. The text literally says Cain was
of the wicked one. Let's go to the
screen and you'll see that that word of
in the Greek is simply X meaning out of
a primary preposition denoting origin,
an action proceeding from or out of a
place.
In other words, beloved,
what the text is saying is that Cain was
of or proceeded from the serpent.
He was serpent seed.
Y'all put a one on the tell if you're
following so far. Abel represented the
seed of the righteous. Cain represented
the seed of the wicked. He was
animalistic.
Cain was animal seed. In other words, if
we can say it this way,
Cain represents those made, listen
carefully to me all, Cain represents
those made in the image of the beast,
while Abel would represent those made in
the image of God. Put a five in the chat
if you're following so far.
Put a five in the chat if you're
following so far. Now, I want you to
notice the nature of beasts. In Psalms
80:13, for example, God is here
describing uh how Israel is his vine and
what's going to happen to his vine. And
he says here in verse 13, "The bore out
of the wood doth waste it, and the wild
beast of the field doth devour it."
Talking about devouring God's people.
Beasts devour. Beasts kill. Beasts act
off of instinct. Notice with me Job
chapter 38:39.
Wilt thou hunt to prey for the lion or
fill the appetite of the young lions
when they couch in their dens and abide
in the covert to lie and wait? The
nature of a beast is to hunt, is to
pounce, is to look for something to
devour.
Y'all put a one in the chat if you're
following.
Put a one in the chat if you're
following. The nature of the beast is to
look for something to devour. In other
words, let me say it this way. When Cain
adopted or took on the nature of the
beast, he was dehumanized.
Put a six in the chat. Six in the chat.
Pastor, we get you. We're following you.
Cain was dehumanized. He didn't take on
the image of God. He took on the image
of the beast. And in taking on the image
of the beast, he was dehumanized.
How do we know this? If we go back to
Genesis 4:5, uh the Bible says, "But
unto Cain," so remember Cain and Abel
both bring an offering unto God. And the
Bible says, "But unto Cain, and to his
offering, God had not respect, and Cain
was very wroth, and his countenance
fell." The single indicator
of reflecting the image of the beast is
wrath
is anger.
Cain became angry. It is the sign. It is
the first signal. It is the first
characteristic
of those who have the image of the
beast.
Cain gets angry
and his anger
is now going to be directed somewhere.
You see,
in Ephesians chapter 6:12, we're told
this, "For we wrestle not against flesh
and blood, but against principalities,
against powers, against the rulers of
the darkness of this world, against
spiritual wickedness in high places."
God's people, those who walk in the
image of God, recognize this crucial
truth that we wrestle not against flesh
and blood. In other words, flesh and
blood is not the real enemy.
You should never look at any any human
being and think that human being is my
enemy. Flesh and blood is my enemy. The
Bible says that the spiritual understand
that flesh and blood is not the enemy.
We don't wrestle against flesh and
blood. But note what Cain does. Come
with me to Genesis chapter 4:6. The Lord
said unto Cain, "Why art thou wroth, and
why is thy countenance fallen? If thou
doest well, shalt thou not be accepted?
And if thou doest not well, sin lith at
the door." Some translations say, "Sin
crouches
at the door." So now God is using animal
language.
Sin like a beast is wanting to pounce on
you, Cain.
But Cain, I want you to rule over this
thing. Understand, Cain, that your enemy
is not your brother. Your enemy is not
your brother.
It would have been a beautiful thing if
this guy by the name of Tyler, I don't
remember his last name, if he understood
that as off as he may have thought
Charlie Kirk was, that it was not flesh
and blood, flesh and blood was not his
enemy. But he didn't understand that
truth. Let me tell you something.
Dehumanized people dehumanize people.
In order, listen to me y'all. In order
for the devil to have his way in the
human soul, he must first dehumanize.
And when he dehumanizes,
the dehumanized person has no problem
dehumanizing people. And when you
dehumanize people, the people themselves
become your enemy. You no longer realize
that we wrestle against flesh and blood.
So now you see flesh and blood as the
enemy. And the single,
the single
most evident
sign
that you are in the image of the beast
is when you see individuals
as the enemy.
Come on, let's go back to the story.
Remember 1st Peter 5:8. The Bible says,
"Your your adversary, the devil, as a
roaring lion walketh about seeking whom
he may devour." This is what God is
trying to warn Cain of Cain. Listen, sin
is crouching at your door. Don't let the
beast in. Don't dehumanize yourself,
Cain. Don't allow yourself to be
dehumanized. But Cain did not listen.
And what he does, what does he do
in essence? He says to Abel, "I unfriend
you.
You are the enemy and I unfriend you."
The Bible says in Genesis 4:8, "And Cain
talked with Abel his brother. And it
came to pass when they were in the field
that Cain rose up against Abel his
brother, and slew him. And the Lord said
unto Cain, "Where is Abel thy brother?"
And he said, "I know not. Am I my
brother's keeper?"
Please see how the dehumanization of
Cain led him to be like, "Why should I
care about my brother?
Why should I care about him?"
The evidence that Cain was the seed of
the beast was that Cain was dehumanized.
His brother died and he could have cared
less. his brother died and it didn't
matter to him. You might say, "Who is my
brother?" We'll hold that question for a
moment because you think certainly not
my enemy. My enemy is not my brother for
sure not. But beloved, I'm trying to
tell you something that Satan's plot for
the end of time is to dehumanize the
entire planet.
And the way that he's going to do that
is through wrath.
Cain's countenance fell. He was wroth.
He was angry.
The devil's goal is to turn men from the
image of God into the image of the
beast. And if he can turn you into the
image of the beast through wrath, listen
to me.
In order for you to be dehumanized, he's
got to remove love from your heart. And
once love has been removed from your
heart, wrath takes its place. And when
wrath takes its place, you have been
dehumanized. And dehumanized people
dehumanize
people.
We see this even in the time of Jesus in
chapter in Luke chapter 6. Luke chapter
6 verse 9. The Bible says, "Then said
Jesus unto them, speaking to the
Pharisees, I will ask you one thing. Is
it lawful on the Sabbath days to do good
or to do evil, to save life or to
destroy it? And looking around upon them
all, he said unto the man, "Stretch
forth thine hand?" And he did so, and
his hand was restored whole as the
other. And they, watch this, the leaders
were filled with madness. You know what
madness is? It's wrath.
They became beastlike and commune one
with another what they might do to
Jesus. In other words, they wanted to
kill him just like Cain.
They were filled with wrath, with
madness. Jesus, we unfriend you. Not
that they were ever his friend. We
unfriend you.
It is interesting. Jesus one time
speaking to the to the Pharisees said
unto them in John 8:43, "Why do you not
understand my speech even because you
cannot hear my word? You are of your
father, the devil." Do you remember what
we said earlier about the word of x out
of Jesus is literally saying you
proceeded from your father the devil.
You even though you're a Pharisee even
though you claim to be God's people even
though you claim to be the seed of the
woman you are
a descendant of the serpent in the
garden. You are a descendant of a beast.
You are of your father the devil and the
lust of your father you will do. He was
a murderer from the beginning. Wow. He
was a murderer from the beginning and
abode not in the truth because there is
no truth in him. When he speaketh a lie,
he speaketh of his own for he is a liar
and the father of it. So I want you to
understand now that the reason Jesus
said to them, you can't understand my
words, is because beasts don't
understand words.
Beasts only react off of instinct.
You you can't talk to a dog and say you
know you know dog um I was wondering the
other day I mean you could say come and
sure they get that
lie okay they get that very simple you
cannot have a conversation with a beast
there's no talking to a beast a beast is
just not going to hear you a beast is
just not going to understand notice with
me Psalm 32:9 be ye not as the horse or
as the mule which have no understanding.
There's a reason why God said why Jesus
said to them, "You don't understand my
words because you're of the f you're of
your father." Your father was the
serpent. Beasts can't understand words.
In 2 Peter chapter 2:12, but these as
natural brute beasts made to be taken
and destroyed speak evil of things that
they understand not. Jude 1:10, but
these speak evil of things which they
knew not. But they were n but they know
naturally as but what they know
naturally as brute beasts in those
things they corrupt themselves.
Please understand this concept of the
brute beast
of the beast that cannot hear the
gospel.
God says love your neighbor and you
can't hear that. You can't understand
that. It doesn't compute. You're like
sure I love my neighbor but who is my
neighbor? My neighbor is represent those
in my camp. My neighbor represents those
who believe like I believe. My neighbor
represents those who like the same
things I like. Surely those are my
neighbors, Lord. You must understand
that. And it's like Jesus saying, "You
are like a beast. You can't understand
when I say love your neighbor." Who is
my neighbor, Lord? Oh, it's those who
believe like I do. It's those that are
on my side.
Notice what 1 John chapter 3:15 says.
Who whosoever hateth his brother is a
murderer.
And you know that no murderer has
eternal life abiding in him. Please
listen to me.
You don't have to murder someone
to murder someone.
And to hate someone
means you've already murdered them.
You may not you may not be able to get a
hold of a long gun rifle and be able to
time on climb on top of a roof and sit
there and wait for your hated target to
come.
But just because you never have the
opportunity doesn't mean the thing isn't
in your heart.
You might say to yourself, "Oh yeah, I'd
never do that." But I need you to
understand, beloved, that the beast
image, the beast heart is deceptive
beyond measure.
And so the devil understands that sure
you may not pull the trigger, you may
not go out and grab the knife, but he
knows if he can at least get you to
hate, you are or you are as good as a
murderer. You are demonstrating the seed
of the serpent. You're you just need to
be wroth. That's all that's all he
requires. That's all he wants. just so
you could be wroth.
Ecclesiastes 3:18, the Bible says, "I
set in my heart concerning the estates
of the son of son sons of men that God
might manifest them, that they might
see, that they themselves are beasts."
God is trying to get us to open our eyes
to see, listen, without me, you are a
beast.
If you're not in the image of God, which
image is love, because God is love, then
you are in the image of the beast who
operates instinctly on wrath.
Remember when the disciples were talking
to Jesus and in Luke chapter 9 verse 53
the Bible says this, they did not
receive him because he his face was as
though he was to go to Jerusalem.
talking about this village in which
Jesus uh people rejected Jesus. And when
his disciples James and John saw this,
they said, "Lord, will thou that we
command fire to come down from heaven
and consume them even as Elias did?" But
he turned and rebuked them and said,
"You know not what manner of spirit you
are of?" Wow. You are of.
You are operating like beasts right now.
The son of man has not come to destroy
men's life but to save them. Remember
when Peter said to Jesus, you know, far
be from you to go die.
Look at what Jesus did. Matthew 16:22.
Matthew 16:23. But he turned and said
unto Peter, "Get thee behind me, Peter."
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. Get thee
behind me, Satan. Thou art an offense to
God. You see, Jesus understood that he
was not wrestling against flesh and
blood. He understood that Peter wasn't
the enemy. He understood that these
people in the village weren't the enemy.
He understood that. But his disciples
struggled with that.
It took them some time to begin to
understand. Wait a minute. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. We wrestle not against flesh and
blood, but spiritual wickedness in high
places.
In fact, Ellen White says this in
Christ's triumph in page 270, she says
this. Pilate was convinced that no
evidence of the guilt of Christ could be
sustain sub substantiated.
Notwithstanding the priests and rulers
had declared that he had spoken
blasphemy. But the Jews were under the
inspiration of Satan as was Cain and
other murderers who have determined to
destroy life rather than save it.
Quote, "And they were the more fierce,
saying, He stirth up the people,
teaching throughout all jewelry from
Galilee, beginning from Galilee to this
place. Fierceness,
wrath." They were of the same spirit of
Cain.
Please, are y'all understanding what I'm
saying this? I'm building up to
something, y'all. I'm coming down to our
time. So, we've seen what it was at the
beginning. We've seen what it was in the
days of Jesus. And even Jesus prophesied
of the future when he said this these
words. Matthew 24:12. And because
iniquity shall abound, the love of many
shall wax cold. In other words, beloved,
Jesus said that as time proceeds, people
would get colder and colder.
The love of many would wax cold.
Almost as if people would begin to
rejoice
over the deaths of their enemies.
rejoice over the death of someone they
don't like. That they would become that
cold that they would actually begin to
rejoice.
You see, understand, beloved, that if
Satan can dehumanize you with hate, then
you don't have an issue dehumanizing
other people. Dehumanize people
dehumanize people.
And you'll see this plot. That's why I
call it the devil's dehumanization plot
because he's been running it all through
history in Daniel chapter 7. In Daniel
chapter 7 21, Daniel speaks of this
little horn that made war with the
saints. Daniel 7:21, I beheld and the
same horn made war with the saints and
prevailed against them. And what you
need to understand about this little
horn, beloved, is that this little horn
is on the head of an animal. It's part
of an animal
which signifies that its persecution of
the people of God was because it is of
the seed of the serpent.
We don't have to guess this because the
time period this little horn uh uh uh
persecutes is known as the 1,260
years or the time times and a half. But
when we go to Revelation 12, notice how
Revelation 12:14 puts it.
And to the woman were given two wings of
a great eagle that she might fly into
the wilderness where she has a place
where she's nourished for a time, times,
and a half from the face of the serpent.
Do y'all see this? In Genesis, it was
the woman and the serpent. In
Revelation, it's the woman and the
serpent. In Genesis, it was the seed of
hum of of a human seed and a beastly
seed. We find the same thing in
Revelation chapter 12.
This persecuting power is described as a
dragon, a beast,
while the God's people is described by a
woman. H listen to this y'all. Listen to
this.
Speaking of this beast in Revelation
17:5, she's now described, the beast is
now described as a woman. And the Bible
says in verse 5, "And upon her forehead
was a name written, mystery Babylon the
great, the mother of harlots and
abominations of the earth. And I saw the
woman, listen to me now y'all, I saw the
woman drunk with the blood of the saints
and with the blood of the martyrs."
Beloved, that is the wine
of Babylon,
the blood of the saints that she is
drinking. That is the wine of Babylon.
What do you mean, pastor? Listen. The
text says that it is the wine of the
wrath. Revelation 18:3, for all nations
have drunk of the wine of the wrath of
her fornication. This wine is wrath
wine.
Meaning
those who partake of this are
intoxicated with wrath.
And it is that wrath that leads them to
become drunk with the blood of the
saints. This is what was happening
during the dark ages. That's why the
Bible describes this woman as drunk with
the blood of the saints. It is the same
thing. The wine, the wine of the wrath
is symbolic, listen to me, is symbolic
of their hatred with which leads them
like Cain to kill others.
The wine of the wrath, you guys,
is the fact that they're drinking the
blood of the saints. And now remember
this. You don't have to actually drink
the blood of the saints,
the blood of others to drink the blood
of others. Because Jesus said, "If you
hate your brother, you are already
guilty of the wine of the wrath of
Babylon. You are already guilty of the
blood."
Now, I want you to hear this out because
remember
during the dark ages, this church, this
system
was was was getting drunk on this wine,
this wine of wrath. And what I need to
let help you to understand, beloved, is
that wrath is intoxicating and it
intoxicates others.
So while the church in the dark ages
were dehumanizing people because they
themselves were dehumanized,
full of wrath, full of hate,
persecuting in the name of Jesus, they
could look at another individual and
say, "Yes, you deserve to die." and you
deserve to die because and if you can
imagine the the media of that day,
the media of that day must have surely
given every reason why it was good for
that person to die.
Come on y'all. Maybe you don't want to
say amen, but but it's okay. I'll say it
for you. Amen.
They must have given every reason why.
Hey, listen. It's okay not to mourn this
death. It's okay not to really be
empathetic about this death because here
is why.
But what I need you to understand that
that kind of wrath that had been being
poured out in Europe over centuries
began to produce another effect. It is
what we call the French Revolution. And
I want to read something to you from the
book Dark Darkness Before Dawn. It's
also in the great controversy. But
listen to what she says here. We're
going to put it up on the screen. The
teachings of religious leaders have
opened the door to infidelity, to
spiritualism, and to contempt for God's
law. And upon these leaders rests a
fearful responsibility for the iniquity
that exists in the Christian world. Now,
she's talking about post
French Revolution, but the same
principle applies pre-French revolution.
In other words, listen to me now.
What we're being told here is that this
system Babylon churches that reject the
law of God
in their rejecting the law of God, they
are embibing in the wine of Babylon. And
that wine, the law, if the law is
summarized in love and they are
rejecting the law of God, then they're
rejecting the definition of love. And
they are beginning to act while speaking
about love. they can begin to do things
that are the very opposite of love like
burning people at the stake in the name
of Jesus in the name of God. That's what
happened during the dark ages. And that
kind of mentality, that kind of
hypocrisy led to unbelievers in the
French Revolution going, "Hey, we reject
God and we reject the Bible." And the
wrath that had been being poured upon
upon them that they were forced to drink
now gets them drunk on wrath.
Are y'all following what I'm saying?
The primary responsibility
of the condition of the world today is
primarily because the churches have been
teaching that God's law is done away
with. And if God's law is done away
with, then guess what what you're saying
is it's okay to kill.
It's okay to lie.
It's okay to commit adultery. It's okay.
If it's okay to break the Sabbath, then
it must be okay to do all these other
things. That's what the churches have
been teaching to the world. It's okay.
And now the world begins to get drunk
off of this false doctrine, this false
wine, and it produces wrath in them,
which in turn angers Christians even
more. How can you live like this? How
can you do these things? Don't you see?
Listen to this. The same the same master
spirit that urged in the massacre of St.
Bartholomew
led also in the scenes of the French
Revolution. Wow. Wow. Wow. Wow. Listen
to what she goes on to say. The work
which the papacy had begun, atheism
completed. The one withheld from the
people the truths of the Bible. The
other taught them to reject both the
Bible and its author. the seed sown by
priests and pates was yielding its evil
fruit. And she's speaking specifically
about the French Revolution.
If you want to know why America is in a
condition that it is now, it is because
the churches of America have been
teaching for decades that the law of God
is done away with. That the law of God
does not stand. That you are no longer
under the law. You are under grace. that
you don't need to obey the commandments
because Jesus died on the cross and
therefore uh the Sabbath is done away
with as well as every other commandment.
You just kind of gauge for yourself what
is right or what is wrong. And when that
message is coming from the only place in
which sanity should be coming from,
truth should be coming from, then what
do you expect is going to happen to a
nation?
It's not the people's fault that they're
like, "Oh, the law of God doesn't stand
anymore." It's the churches who've been
teaching that
forever
in this country forever.
And so what happens, beloved, is that
this wine is is it's almost like a it's
a it's a wine that that
it produces more drunkards.
It produces more drunkards. This man,
and I'm coming to this man, this young
man that killed Charlie Kirk was drunk
on the wine of Babylon.
He was drunk on wrath.
We don't know all the reasons for his
wrath, for his anger, but he was
wrathful enough to become dehumanized
and then dehumanize Charlie Kirk and
then kill him. You can't kill unless you
dehumanize first.
And beloved, here's what we need to
understand as God's people.
Because a lot of us get caught up, get
caught up in this cycle of wrath,
not realizing where it's all ending,
where it's all headed.
Listen to me, y'all. The Bible says in
Proverbs 23:20, "They that tarry long at
the wine, they that go to seek mixed
wine. Look not thou upon the wine when
it is red, when it giveth his color in
the cup, when it moveth itself a right.
At the last it biteth like a serpent,
and stingeth like an adder. Thine eyes
shall behold strange women, and thine
heart shall utter perverse things." May
I suggest to you, beloved, that all who
drink the wine of Babylon will
eventually be brought into the system of
Babylon itself. That's what the Bible
tells us. The whole nation, the whole
world is going to finally unite under
the umbrella of Babylon. And the way the
devil gets them to unite is through
wrath.
When you all have the same spirit of the
beast, you will eventually worship the
image of the beast.
If you are reflecting the image of the
beast now when the image of the beast is
actually implemented you will be connect
you will be drawn to it. You will be
attached to it. You will be attracted to
it.
This is why the Bible says in Proverbs
chapter 20 wine is a is a marker. Strong
drink is raging. Beloved, this is why
strong drink is raging. When you begin
to rage, when you begin to adopt the
anger,
adopt the wrath
of the world, it is going to lead even
of the professed church. It is going to
lead to something that is not good in
the end. So, Revelation 12:17 says this,
"And the dragon was wroth with the woman
and went to make war with the remnant of
her seed, which keep the commandments of
God and have the testimony of Jesus
Christ." The devil's end game is to turn
the entire world anger toward the
church.
And so many of us in the church are busy
hyping up the anger of the world, hyping
up the anger of those we agree with.
And beloved, don't get me wrong. There
are things in the world to be angry
about. But there's a difference between
righteous indignation and false
righteous indignation. And the problem
is that many of us cannot make it out.
Because when godly anger will never lead
you to see people as the beast,
godly anger will never lead you to see
flesh and blood as the enemy. It will
always lead you to understand that we
wrestle not against flesh and blood. I
know those people are doing this, but
they think what they're doing is right.
They think what they're doing is good.
And I get it, but they're not. And
they're deceived. And what can we do to
help those people? It's not, oh, those
people are wicked and let's make let's
let's expose these wicked people. No, we
should expose wickedness, but realize,
beloved, that we are not wrestling
against people. We're not wrestling
against flesh and blood. No matter how
much the devil comes into Peter and
tries to get Jesus to say, "Peter,
you're wicked." Jesus knew Satan, get
thee behind me.
The devil's goal is to get the entire
world drunk on the wine of Babylon.
And watch this. When the Bible says that
the wine of Babylon is given by this
woman, remember a woman represents a
church. So now now what the text is
telling us is that at the end of time
the devil will use a counterfeit
righteous indignation
because it's coming from the woman.
She's angry over how the world is not
following God. She's angry over all the
unrighteousness in the world and all the
wicked. Meanwhile, meanwhile, it's the
very same system that is teaching that
the law of God is done away with, that
you don't need to keep the commandments.
It's that very same system that is
attempting to put in place a Christian
nationalistic a aocracy
to solve the problem that lies at her
feet.
And so now Jesus says in John 16:2,
"They shall put you out of the
synagogues. Yay, the time is coming
where he that kills you will think he is
doing God's service.
The time is coming where he who is angry
with you will think they're being angry
with you in the name of Jesus. Do you
know how many how many of us in the
church are angry with other people in
the church and we think that it is a
holy anger? We think it is holy
righteousness. I unfriend you.
I unfriend you.
Do you know? Do you know how many of us
are being trained to see flesh and blood
as the enemy
as we continue to see uh uh um uh videos
put up of people and what this person in
the church does and what this and it's
all designed. Beloved, listen to me.
Social media today is crazy because it's
all designed to channel hate toward an
individual.
The devil knows that hate is a powerful
motivator.
So if he can dehumanize you,
then he can lead you to dehumanize
others.
You see, I was listening to the news uh
um earlier and they were saying that
this the killer of Charlie Kirk said
that Charlie Kirk was full of hate and
spreading hate. Now, I want you to get
catch catch this philosophy.
This 22-year-old man said Charlie Kirk
was full of hate and spreading hate. And
I'm against that. So, what I'm going to
do is do something hateful.
How does that work?
Love has to be moved out of the way in
order for the dehumanized in order for
people to become dehumanized and then
they can de dehumanize other people.
Wrath takes a place of love. The more
the less love you have in your heart for
someone, the more wrath is automatically
placed there.
And so what I want you to understand,
beloved, is that this wine has this
effect where it intoxicates thousands of
people at a time.
There are people
who who were dancing when they heard
Charlie Kirk died.
I want you to think about that for a
moment. People were dancing and
celebrating
saying, "Well, he said not to have
empathy, so I'm not going to have
empathy." But I need you to understand,
beloved, that that whether that
statement is right or wrong, don't have
empathy or or or you know, empathy is a
weakness, whatever,
the fact
that we're at a place in our society now
where people are dancing and celebrating
a death
should scare everybody. But it doesn't
stop there
because you have a whole another group
of people who are saying it is time for
war.
Professed Christian people saying it is
time for war. It is time for revenge,
for vengeance. And I'm I'm what I'm
trying to show you, beloved, is the plot
of the enemy to to get a spirit of to
get the spirit of wrath. wrath. The
spirit of the beast so ingrained in the
human heart,
whether it is openly unrighteous or
disguised under righteousness,
you got to understand how this thing
spreads.
See, see, a after this assassination
attempt, a I'm sorry, after this
assassination, this ungodly
assassination,
H.B.CU schools just got sh tons of them.
Virginia State University, my old
school, Oaka University, the school I
went to after Adventist school, shut
down because of death threats,
most likely coming from people who claim
to be
Christians, American Christians,
American patriots, people who are like,
"Hey, God, country, what most likely
coming from that se because they're
angry about." And you see what happens?
The anger, it just keeps it just keeps
spiraling and spiraling and spiraling.
And the more it spirals is, the more it
draws people into its cup.
The devil, his goal, his plot is to
dehumanize
and make you think you have the right to
be dehumanized.
This this m the
People are like, "How can you be dancing
at Charlie Kirk?" And now watch this.
There were some Democratic senators,
husband and wife, who were assassinated
a few months back.
And just as now, people are saying,
"Where's the outcry for Charlie Kirk?"
Many of those same people who are
saying, "Where's the outcry?"
Not a word
about that assassination.
And now if you turn on the news, I need
y'all to see what's going on here. But I
need you to put down the cup please and
see what's going on.
Because now what's going on is oh this
group of people, this political group of
people, they are assassins. They are
murderers. No, no, no. This group of
murderers.
What is time for war?
This country may very well be headed for
a civil war.
And if you know anything about prophecy,
if you've read the writings of the
spirit of prophecy, you will see that
she says a civil war will return to
America.
The devil is seeking to dehumanize
and to have all those who he dehumanize
think they have the right
to be dehumanized.
Beloved, our world is becoming a scary
place. This Ukrainian woman
that was stabbed on the the the train in
Charlotte, I think it's Charlottesville,
and I think to my, you know,
Let me tell you
and let me let me let me
like
I don't understand how an entire
car car full of people saw this and let
that woman just die there.
Let that woman let that man get away.
And I know he got caught in, you know,
eventually.
But
when we get to the place where we become
so desensitized
to, am I my brother's keeper? We have
that mentality, that attitude. I need
you to understand that what the devil is
doing, beloved, he is he is dehumanizing
the planet. And many Adventists are
getting caught up in this dehumanization
process. I'm coming to that. Please
listen to me, y'all.
Many of us are getting caught up. You
could just look at the at Facebook
comments and just see the dehumanization
process within our church, within our
members growing stronger and stronger
and stronger.
We rejoice when we hear that those who
don't agree with us, something has
happened to them or we just say, "Hey,
my silence is my rejoicing." That's how
we do it.
The Bible says in Proverbs 24:17,
"Rejoice not when thine enemy fallth,
and let not thine heart be glad when he
stumble, lest the Lord see it, and it
displeased many, he turn away his wrath
from him." Beloved, we should never be
rejoicing.
We should never be rejoicing. That is
the spirit of the enemy.
When George Floyd had a knee put on his
neck
and people were like, "Oh, he deserved
it. Oh, he was a criminal."
Let let me tell you,
the dehumanization process will always
seek to justify why it's okay to
dehumanize an individual.
And we're watching it unfold before our
very eyes.
We're watching this process unfold
before our very eyes where we can see a
death and be like, "He probably deserved
it."
Or we can see a death and be like, "No
need to intervene. No need to stop." Or
we can see a death and rejoice. Listen
y'all,
I want to take these three because
they're an example of what's happening
in the world around us. Charlie Kirk's
death, people dancing.
this Ukrainian woman's death, people
standing by and not doing anything
at least for a time. George Floyd, uh,
he deserved it. I need you to understand
how the devil is is is fulfilling this
plot. And now you might say, well, well,
how is this happening? Uh, uh, even in
the church or how is this happening on
such a large scale? Let me tell you how
it's happening, you guys.
The way that it's happening is this. If
the devil can get you to become
suspicious of flesh and blood, he has
already got you sealed up. So now what's
happening is that we're getting to a
place where where we're looking at
different organizations and now we're
looking at the people in those
organizations saying, "Yeah, those
people are beasts. They are animals."
Let me give you the exhibit, y'all. The
United Nations. Yeah, it's good for us.
It's all right for us to be angry and to
say those people in the United Nations,
they know what they're doing and there's
a plot and there's this and there's that
or the World Economic Forum or the CDC
or the Republicans or the Democrats or
the deep state. We can see these things
and go, "Yo, the the people there are
wicked." And the moment that the devil
can get us to to to
embrace the concept of flesh and blood
as our enemy,
it's the people in the Democratic party.
It's the people in the Republican party.
It's the people in the CDC that trying
to kill us with this vaccine. It's the
people at the United Nations.
It's the people in the LGBT community.
It's the people on the left. It's the
people on the right. It's the people in
BLM. It's the pe once we get to thinking
this way.
And you see, here's what we don't
understand, you guys.
When when when God talks about Babylon,
you understand he's not talking about
the people.
He's talking about the system.
And this is why in Revelation 18:4, the
Bible says, "I heard another voice from
heaven saying, "Come out of her,
Babylon, my people, that you be not
partakers of her sin and that you
receive not of her plagues." God knows
how to separate system from people. So,
while beloved, we believe that the papal
system is a is a is an anti-Christian
system, we don't go around saying that
the people in the system are crooked and
liars and wicked and animals and beasts
and and whatever happens to them, they
deserve it. We don't do that.
Even though we believe that that the the
the Christian nationalist movement is a
fulfillment of Bible prophecy,
Revelation 13:11, we don't say the
people in it are wicked. At least we
shouldn't say the people in it are
wicked. They don't know what they're
doing.
Listen y'all. If Jesus himself, if Jesus
knew that Satan was moving in those
Roman soldiers and moving in in in in
the Pharisees and Jesus himself prayed
to the father, saying they don't know
what they're doing.
Now, if anyone ever had the right to
say, "Yep, they are conspiring to do
something that they know is Jesus is the
one that could have been like, "Yep,
it's the people." It's not even Satan,
it's the people. But Jesus himself said
they know not what they do.
How should we be treating people in the
LGBT community?
How should we be treating people
in a party that you may not agree with?
who have embraced racism?
How should we be treating people who
have embraced philosophies we don't
agree with? How should we be treating
people who have embraced doctrines that
we don't agree with? How should we be
treating people?
Jesus says, "Greater love has no man
than this, that a man lay down his life
for his friends."
who are his friends.
No, Jesus didn't point to someone who
agrees with you. Jesus didn't point to
those who have your philosophy. Jesus
didn't point to those who who act like
you and look like you and and and are
your skin color. Jesus pointed to the
ones that the Jews thought were their
enemies the most. That's your brother.
And so many of us, beloved, in the
church, we have this this smug
righteous indignation that we can just
tell people they're wicked and tell
people that they support this or that
and thus they are this and that and and
and you're this and and and listen
y'all, it's so infiltrating the church
that we now see that same spirit even
towards our own leadership, even towards
the general conference. We are now
trained. Oh, you're a liberal. You're a
conservative. I hate you. Oh, you're in
the leadership. And we have this spirit
of disdain, this spirit of wrath,
and we buy into these these these these
uh uh these suspicions.
There is no place that made it more
clearer
than the COVID issue.
Instead of us adopting a spirit of hey,
if you want to be vaccinated, that's
fine. And if you don't want to be
vaccinated, that's fine. No, no, no, no.
It had to be you are the enemy if you
got vaccinated or you are the enemy if
you don't get vaccinated.
It had it couldn't be we wrestle wrestle
not against flesh and blood. No, no, no.
It had to be you bowed your knee to
Babylon. You're preparing to receive the
mark of the beast. It couldn't just be,
"Hey, you were convicted to get it. You
were convicted not to get it. Let every
man be convicted in his own mind." It
couldn't be that. Nope. Nope. Nope.
There was a conspiracy. No, no, no.
There was going to be this was going to
be the beginning of it. Had to be
something. And beloved, when we have
that disposition that that we have to
find an enemy for a cause, we have to
it's got to be flesh and blood
somewhere. And therefore I unfriend you.
I unfriend you. I unfriend you. Do you
know how much unfriending happened over
CO?
Do you know how many people have
unfriended one another, not realizing
that the devil is planting the spirit,
the very spirit of wrath, and it's only
going deeper and deeper and deeper?
Watch this y'all. Listen to this quote
from the Great Controversy, page 608.
Ellen White says this. As the storm
approaches, a large class who have
professed faith in the third angel's
message, but have not been sanctified
through obedience to the truth abandoned
their position and join the ranks of the
opposition. Now, pause for a second. Who
are the ranks of the opposition?
We know that the ranks of the opposition
represents the papal and apostate
Protestant systems.
What we're being told here in this
statement is that at the end of time
they're going to be Adventists who join
the papacy and apostate Protestantism.
They have become so enamored
with the wrath of these systems. What
are you angry at? What are you angry?
Oh, we're angry at this. Okay, we're an
And it's a righteous indignation. Here's
what she goes on to say. by uniting with
the world and partaking of its spirit of
its spirit. She calls these systems the
world even though it's the church. She
calls it the spirit of the world because
it is a beastly spirit. She says by
partaking of its spirit, they have come
to view matters in nearly the same
light. In other words, they're on the
same page with everything that's that
apostate Protestantism and and and the
papacy are they believe their
philosophies. They're now on the same
page.
By uniting with the world and partaking
of its spirit, they have come to view
matters in nearly the same light. And
when the test is brought, they are
prepared to choose the easy and popular
side. You know what's going to be the
popular side at this time? It's not
going to be atheism.
It's going to be the image of the beast.
That's where everybody's going to be
flocking to. Men of talent and pleasing
address. Men who were well-known. Men
who could throw down men who who had
podcasts and and all. Men who
men
of talent and pleasing address who once
rejoice in the truth employ their powers
to deceive and mislead souls. They
become the most bitterest and bitter
enemies of their former brethren when
Sabbath keepers are brought before the
courts to answer for their faith. These
apostates are the most efficient agents
of Satan. You might be like, "Nah, that
that could never be. That could never
be." But listen beloved, if you're
partaking of the wrath of Babylon now,
a pseudo wrath
against unrighteousness,
a wrath that points people that points
to people as the enemy. They are wicked.
They are against us. They have declared
war. This is war. They are the enemy.
beloved, without understanding Jesus's
distinction that we wrestle not against
flesh and blood. I listen y'all.
The papacy, the issue with the papacy is
its teaching. The people in it are
simply deceived.
They're not wicked. They're not
plotting. They're not like, "Oh man, how
can we how can we help the devil get his
plan across?" Beloved, no. No. That's a
very childish approach to prophecy.
And so what we need to understand,
beloved, is that we must have the spirit
of Jesus who said they know not what
they do.
Jesus was God. If they knew what they
were doing, he would not have said that.
And yet he said they know not what they
do. Beloved, we have to come to that
same conclusion. Listen, this system is
wicked. It may be corrupt. It may be
this, that, but they don't know what
they're doing. They think they're doing
the right thing. And I disagree with
them. Biblically, they're not doing the
right thing, but they don't know that.
I'm giving them the benefit of the
doubt. Why? Because I am my brother's
keeper. That's my brother. People aren't
literally trying to kill you with drugs.
People aren't literally out to Listen,
y'all. People are even when they are
wrong in their position, they're doing
what they think is the best way to go
forward.
And if we don't have that spirit, we're
going to continue to hate one another.
And listen, there's no turning back.
This is a turning point. It is only
going to get worse.
Let me let me say it now. It is only
going to get worse. The question is, am
I going to partake of that wine?
Listen to me again, you guys.
There are things to be genuinely angry
about. Righteous indignation. I get
that.
I get that. Unrighteousness.
Yes. Yes. When people are getting
murdered. Yes. Yeah. Racism. Yes. Yes.
You can go down the list of things that
that that deserve righteous indignation.
Senseless murders.
But beloved, how we respond.
When we respond with it's vengeance
time, when we respond with I hate you,
when we respond with I hate them, you
are already caught in the enemy's trap.
We're getting ready to close. I want you
to listen to this. I want you to listen
to this.
When Saul dies,
David doesn't rejoice.
Listen what David did. The Bible says,
"Then David took hold of his clothes and
rent them, and likewise all the men that
were with him, and they mourned and wept
and fasted until even for Saul and for
Jonathan his son, and for the people of
the Lord, and for the house of Israel,
because they were fallen by the sword."
I want you to see how David treated
Saul.
When Jesus was on the cross, he prayed,
"Father, forgive them." Luke 23:34,
"Father, forgive them for they know not
what they do." And I want you to listen
to what Ellen White says about this.
Listen to what Ellen White says about
this. Then I've got one more verse and
we're going to close up.
She says this. While the soldiers were
doing their fearful work, Jesus prayed
for his enemies. Father, forgive them
for they know not what they do. His mind
passed from his own suffering to the sin
of his persecutors and the terrible
retribution that would be theirs. No
curses were called down upon the
soldiers who were handling him so
roughly. No vengeance was invoked upon
the priests and rulers who were gloating
over the accomplishment of their
purpose. Christ pied them in their
ignorance and guilt.
He breathed only a plea for their
forgiveness, for they know not what they
do. And now listen what she says. Had
they known that they were putting to
torture one who had come to save the
sinful race from eternal ruin, they
would have been seized with remorse and
horror. But their ignorance did not
remove their guilt. For it was their
privilege to know and accept Jesus as
their savior. Some of them would yet see
their sin and repent and be converted.
Some by their impenitence would make it
impossible for the prayer of Christ to
be answered for them. Yet just the same,
God's purpose was reaching its
fulfillment. Jesus was earning the right
to become the advocate of men in the
father's presence. And then this last
paragraph, that prayer of Christ for his
enemies embraced the whole world. It
took in every sinner that has lived or
should live from the beginning of the
world to the end of time. Upon all rest
the guilt of crucifying the son of God.
To all forgiveness is freely offered.
Whosoever will may have the peace with
may have peace with God and inherit
eternal life. Beloved, I want to appeal
to you
that you drop the spirit of wrath,
that you drop the spirit of anger, even
the disguise of righteous indignation
against people.
We need to stop demonizing people. God
has not called us to demonize people
because if the people are the demons,
then our targets are going to be people.
And we have not been called to target
people. We've been called to target
systems. We've been called to say
Babylon is fallen is fallen. And when
we're focused on the system, beloved, we
can we can despise the system and yet
love the people.
But the people aren't lovely. That
doesn't matter. But the people are are
acting like beasts. That doesn't matter.
God's call is to is to walk them from
the image of the beast back to the image
of God. It is to show them what Christ
does in the heart to transform the
character. And beloved, as long as we
see each other as the enemy, as long as
we are in the mindset of I unfriend you,
that I unfriend you will ultimately lead
to the point in time where they
It will lead to the point in time where
whosoever does not worship the image of
the beast should be killed and killed in
the name of righteousness. That's where
this is headed. Jo
Lord, help me to put down the wrath
and pick up your love. Help me to live
by that principle that we wrestle not
against flesh and blood. It is not the
people, it is the systems. It is the
systems that get into the minds of the
people and tell the people think this
way, act this way, walk this way. And we
our target is not the people. It is the
system. Lord, teach us to understand
that we wrestle not against flesh and
blood. Because you know what? The world
is not going to get this lesson.
And the wrath of the world will
eventually be turned upon you and upon
me.
You will be called a criminal.
You will be called a crook.
It will be said of you that your
your death is worthy. Your death has a
noble cause. You should die because you
are not following along.
social media will say of you, "Yeah, he
deserved to die. She deserved to die.
And this is why."
And so, beloved, if you feed into that
spirit now, you're simply feeding the
very spirit that will either swallow you
up and make you one of them,
make you embibe in that same spirit, or
the very spirit that will eventually
turn on you. Why would you feed that
spirit?
My appeal today,
I want to read it to you. John 15:12-14.
This is my commandment that you love one
another as I have loved you. Greater
love has no man than this, that a man
lay down his life for his friends. You
are my friends if you do what whatsoever
I command you.
If you were sitting next to Charlie Kirk
and you saw that gun
and you knew that you had the power to
save this man or to have him killed.
If you were on that train
and you saw that man take out that knife
to go attack that
defenseless woman.
If you were there
when George Floyd had that knee on his
neck,
I want you to ask yourself,
what would I have done? If I could go
back and change the hands of time, what
would I have done?
Greater love has no man this than a man
laid down his life for his friends.
Jesus said in Matthew 10:22, "You shall
be hated of all nations for my name's
sake, but he that endureth unto the end,
the same shall be saved." Endure in
what? Endure in love.
The love of many is waxing cold. And
it's waxing cold even in the church.
Beloved, it is my prayer.
It is my prayer that we will take our
weapons off of one another. That we will
learn to stop targeting people
inside the church and outside the
church. That we will deal with the
philosophies, with the systems, deal
with those. But beloved, leave the
people alone.
Love the people.
Pray for the people. Be willing to die
for the people.
Love the people.
That is what God has called us to do. If
it's your desire to live by that
principle that we wrestle not against
flesh and blood but against spiritual
wickedness in high places where you will
stop seeing the people as the enemy.
Stop seeing the pastors, the people, the
leaders, the GC this, the GC that, the
CDC, the the Democrats, the Republicans,
the stop seeing the people as the
problem and focus on what God has called
us to do. He's called us to call out
Babylon and call a people out of
Babylon. If that is your desire to say,
"Lord, I'm going to love every soul and
distinguish between the philosophy and
the person." Help me, Lord, that I do
not become dehumanized.
Put that one in the chat. Lord, help me
that I never become dehumanized
and that I will not dehumanize other
people whether I agree with them
or not. If that's your desire, put that
one in the chat
and let us pray that God will make this
a reality in our lives
because beloved, the love of many is
waxing cold. Let's pray. Heavenly
Father, thank you for your love for us.
Thank you that you loved us even while
we were yet your enemies. Lord, with
everything going on in this world around
us, people are calling for vengeance.
People are calling for civil war. And
Lord, if we as a church don't get it
together before these things really
start to go down, we're going to get
swept up in the wrath. And many of us
are already drinking of the wine of this
wrath. Please, Lord,
show us,
show us how to live as you lived. Show
us how to be in your image and not the
image of the beast.
And Lord, please seal the spirit of love
in our hearts that we may know that our
enemy is not flesh and blood, but
spiritual wickedness in high places.
Thank you, Lord. And train us to see
beyond flesh and blood is our prayer in
Jesus name. Amen. And amen. I want to
thank you all for tuning in and we're
going to go ahead and put the link in
the chat for the afterglow. Uh so please
uh we encourage you to to to jump on. We
invite you to join us and we're going to
talk about Sabbath school. We'll talk
about the the uh the uh message today
and you'll get to share your thoughts
and we'll get to fellowship together.
And so again, may God bless you and keep
you and may God keep your eyes focused
on Jesus. In his name we pray. Amen. God
bless you.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]